# **UMER AZIZ**

## PERSONAL DETAILS

New Mirpur , Pakistan 10250 umeraziz682@gmail.com, +923089752092 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/umer-aziz-b13b841b2

### **SUMMARY**

I am a passionate and experienced MERN STACK Web Developer with more than 4 years of experience and I have a Bachelor of Science degree in Software Engineering. I have expertise in building and maintaining Front-end web applications covered by testing. For the last 4+ years, I have been with HTML, CSS, SASS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT REDUX, TAILWINDCSS, BOOTSTRAP, MONGODB, and NODE JS. I am dedicated to building state-of-the-art web applications. To date, I try to use the latest technologies to build products that bring your ideas into reality.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **BS - SOFTWARE ENGINEERING**

Oct 2019 - Oct 2023

MIRPUR UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, New Mirpur AJK, Pakistan

### EXPERIENCE

#### MERN Stack developer

Mar 2021 - Present

Upwork

- Converting Figma Design into HTML / CSS
- Creating Responsive Website Using Tailwind CSS, React.js & Next.js
- Delivered front- and back-end development across mobile and web applications.

#### Web developer intern

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

DigiDolph, New Mirpur , Pakistan

- Collaborated with web designers to match visual design intent.
- Enhanced front-end performance through image optimization and clean coding practices, accelerating load times.
- Developed and tested REST APIs to check API responds with wide variety of requests.

## **Web developer**Newday, North Holland , Netherlands

Dec 2021 - Jun 2022

- Collaborating with designers, other developers, and project managers to understand project requirements and translate them into technical specifications
- Writing clean, well-documented, and maintainable code that follows best practices and coding standards
- Staying updated with industry trends, new technologies, and development methodologies to continuously enhance skills and knowledge

## SKILLS

Interpersonal skills	Teamwork & leadership skills
Problem solving	Good communication & listening skills
Learning Agility	Analytical Thinking
Time Management	Excellent coding skills in various programming languages
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION	
Microsoft Office	HTML / CSS
Bootstrap / Tailwind CSS	React.js / Next.js
MongoDB	Node.js
Git	Web Development
English	Urdu